Alright, the job has run data is right here.
But how do we know if the data that is loaded here is
as per our expectations, what we,
we have set in the web mapping sheet, right?
Our code is supposed to do what is right here.
And of course we have used ai,
but we still have to do our unit testing.
It's called unit testing.
What we've been doing so far is development.
And as a part of development, we also have
to unit test our code we build, right?
So the output of the code is of course data in curate layer.
So we wanna test that whether it has really done its job
as per expectation or not.
So we gotta be validate all of this logic that is what
we should be doing in unit testing.
And also the data quality rules as well.
We gotta be validating these as well in unit testing.
So how can we now validate, okay,
how can we now do our unit testing?
So this data here, if you see is in par K format.
We even if you to download this
and open that, you cannot really open that.
And we have so many partitions.
So how do you then check data in all the files?
What's the strategy? Yeah, can you just think
for a moment how we can do that?
We, you have actually used a step I will be recommending now
in the past, just pause the video
and think how you can actually look at the data
within the parq file.
Okay? I hope you've already seen that.
So the next step obviously is to create tables on top
of this data, right?
Tables in a glue catalog. So that is what we'll do now.
But before that, remember you also have
rejection being done, right?
There was some data which if you remember,
did not meet these data quality rules and they got rejected.
So that information is also getting captured in the
log by our code.
Okay? So you're gonna go back to our blue console
and look at the logs here, click on the output logs,
it opens this CloudWatch log.
And if you scroll down towards the end,
it shows the initial record count for the two years is
around four 40 million records.
There were, there was some validation that was done.
And then we had
so many valid records, so many rejected records.
And the final count of records return
to S3 is four three 5 million records,
approximately four 35 million records, which,
and this number matches the wallet records.
This is what is in the log.
But we also should be validating that by
firing the queries on the BlueCat log table, which points to
this dataset, this entire dataset in curated folder.
We're gonna copy this, uh, S3 URI we see here.
And then we'll go back to, uh, glue console
and then we'll go to the data catalog.
And within this we'll go to crawler at,
click open in a new tab.
So we already have the crawler that we had before.
We'll just choose this one and go to action
and duplicate crawler.
And we can simply edit the path here, right?
We can simply edit the path, choose S3,
Add it, and then this time we will
actually crawl curated folder.
Okay. And then we'll update the source.
We'll then go to next here.
We don't want to over at the previous table,
so we'll now we'll just, uh, have a prefix as curated.
That way the previous table, which is pointing
to the raw table doesn't get updated.
And then we'll just do a next
and then we'll just, uh, come down.
And then finally we'll just create crawler.
And then we will simply run this
and wait for this to finish.
We'll just refresh it here. It's already running.